Guide to the Malcolm Goldstein Papers MSS.350
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Music Projects
  - Subseries A: Projects A-Z
    - "Marin's Song, Illuminated": "Marin's Lied, Illuminiert" - Horspiel (radio acoustic art), WDR (West German Radio) Cologne, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "Marin's Song, Illuminated" Time of Music [photographs], 1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "Marin's Song of Origin" [score], 1978 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - "A meditation/ responses" to Charles Ives' "Unanswered Question" [score], 2006 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - "Metal Garden" performed with "Sheep Meadow" at Bowdoin College [photographs by Kathy Bradford], 1979 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - "Moments" for Yoriko and Gabriel Chodos [score], May, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - "Montreal Miniature" collage for radio [score], February 2, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - "Mountains and Rivers Remain", 2018 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - "Name pieces" ("Naming Songs")- a short song for Christian Wolff, a sounding of Udo Kasemets, "Naming Song for Tom Plsek", January 3, 1996; November 27, 2000; October 1, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - "A New Song of many faces for In These Times", 2002 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "Of Sky Bright Mushrooms Bursting in My Head" [score], October 29, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - "An old fiddler stomping" for Bill Royer [score], February, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - "On and on and always slowly nowhere" [score], 2011 (Box 6, Folder 23, Box 51, Folder 6)
    - "On and On and Always Slowly Nowhere", 2019 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - "On the edge of song" [score], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - "On the first day of spring there werer forty pianos" [score], January, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "On the first day of spring there werer forty pianos" - photographs of premier with invitations and responses, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "On the first day of spring there werer forty pianos" Response cards, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "On Withered Fields Wandering Still" [score], 2010 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "On Withered Fields, Wandering Still"-"L'Oubli de l'air" installation by Lani Maestro [inkjet prints], 2010 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Once" collaboration with Barbara Hammam and Mischa Murucher [Includes score for "Once (again)"], April 30, 1998; September 14-17, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "Orchestra Pieces": "Pond: 'earth's eye', the mirror" and "Night Chant" [score], 1980; 1985 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "...out of changes: Keeping Still; Mountain" [score], 1994 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "...out of changes: Keeping Still; Mountain" photographs of collages by Fanny Schoning ("I-Ging Series"), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "...out of changes: Keeping Still; Mountain" traces of collages by Fanny Schoning ("I-Ging Series"), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "...out of changes: Keeping Still; Mountain" with Fanny Shoning, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "out of nowhere... and there to again" [score], November 30, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - "Overture to Fantastic Gardens" [score], 1964; September, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Percussion Music- "Wood Stone Metal Skin, With Voice"; "The RIch Complex Vocabulary of a Percussionist's Body/Gesure", 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - "Piano Studies" [score], August, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "Place: A convergence of distances" sound installation with tape collage- Switzerland, October, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - "Process, or Time Between," "Thinking About Gagaku," "Walking with Samuel Beckett", 2020 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - "Qaumaneq; shaking with joy" [score], 1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "Qerneraq; our breath as bones" [score], October, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - "Radio Play Music" [score], 1989 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - "...a reflection. It is" [score], November, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - "Regarding the Tower of Babel" [music/theater piece], 1997 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - "Regarding the Tower of Babel" English Text [score], December 23, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - "Regarding the Tower of Babel" French typed version [score], June 23, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - "Die Reise des Spatzen (oder Die Liebe zur Heimat)", 1993 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - "Renga (La metamorphose de la source)" [score], 1997 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - "Resonances de Babel" with photoraphs by Thierry Collins and mural by Natasha Mayers, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - "Resonances de la Fontaine" [score], 2012 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "Royalty House Blues (Cantos III)" [score], September, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "Sanctuary Piece" for Cindy Childs [score], June, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - "Scherzo" for James Waring [score], 1964 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "The Seasons" a collection of sounds and textures- original concept sketch, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "The Seasons" notes and notations for the Kurtzforum Art Series Journal, October, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "The Seasons: Vermont" [score], 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "The Seasons: Vermont" [score: instructions without graphic score pages], 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "Seikilos Song" (arrangement for student ensemble at Goddard College), 1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "A Shifting of Focus" [score], 2010 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - "A Short Song for Christian" (Wolff)[score], January 3, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - "A Sick Eagle Can You See" from Charles Ives [score], December 15, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - "Sirens for Edgard Varese" [score], December, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "the sky has many stories to tell" for The Locrian Chamber Players [score], 2010 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "Song of the Thundercloud/ Rainbow, Becoming" piano solo for Jim Tenney [score], August 14, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - "Le Souffle du Coyote a la Surface de l'Eau" a radio piece for "Le Navire Night" (Helene Prevost) Societe Radio Canada, January 23, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Sounding the Fragility of Line" for Morton Feldman - violin alone and cello adaptation, January 21, 1988; 1999 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "Sounding a Nimbus for Geoff" [score], 2011 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "Soundings" on the canal boat "Spreekomtess"- Maerz Musik/ Berliner Festspiele [photographs with video stills by Barbara Hammann], March, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - "Soundings" [photographs by Bill Hellerman], 1978 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - "Soweto Stomp" with "Been in the storm so long" and "I have a dream" speech [score], 1985 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - "State of the Nation" for Judson Gallery Publication, October, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "Stillness Unfolding"- dance and sound structure, February, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - "A Summoning of Focus" for Joseph Celli [score], January, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - "...that hung like fire on heaven" reduced size conductor's score, set of parts, and instruction pages [score], November 28, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - "...that hung like fire on heaven" instrumental parts [score], 1985 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - "...that hung like fire on heaven" permission letter for quote from 'Let Us Now Praise Famous Men', September 30, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - "...that hung like fire on heaven" hymn for Martin Luther King, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - "...that hung like fire on heaven" instrumental parts from performance [score], 1985 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - "...that hung like fire on heaven" photocopied parts [score], 1985 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - "...that hung like fire on heaven" reduced size conductor's score and instructions with Martin Luther King Jr.'s Washington D.C. speech, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - "...that hung like fire on heaven" notation explanations in score and parts, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - "That is poetry as" musical transformation of the mesostic "I have nothing to say..." by John Cage [score], 1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - "That Which Goes On", 2016 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - "This Full Breath/Gesture Sounding", 2017 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - "Through Deserts of Time" in memoriam for Morris Block, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - "Topography of a Sound Mind" Horspiel WDR Koln [radio], 1991; 1994 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "(Trinity) Extended... Meets the Passumpsic" [score], August 30, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "Two Seeking Song, Listening" (Page 6 Replacement), 2014 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - "Two Silences" from "Cento Anni Di Suoni"- original score with revised versions, 2000; 2003; 2013 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - "Typography of a Sound Mind" for John Cage, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - "Uber Land Unter" (over land under) with Dorethea Rust [1 of 3], April, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Uber Land Unter" (over land under) with Dorethea Rust [2 of 3][photographs], April, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - "Uber Land Unter" (over land under) with Dorethea Rust [3 of 3], April, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - "Upon the string, within the bow...breathing" [score], 1972 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - "Versuch einer Grundlichen Violinschule" ("Essay on the Fundamentals of Violin Playing") materials for horspiel [score][1 of 3], 1996 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - "Versuch einer Grundlichen Violinschule" ("Essay on the Fundamentals of Violin Playing") materials for horspiel [score][2 of 3], 1996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - "Versuch einer Grundlichen Violinschule" ("Essay on the Fundamentals of Violin Playing") materials for horspiel [score][3 of 3], 1996 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - "The Violence of Small Sounds" [score], 1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - "The Violence of Small Sounds" [Photographs], 1984-1987 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - "Violin Solos the (Whole) World Plays, or The 'Third' World Within Us" with "Tongues of My Mother's Teaching" magnetic tape collage, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - "Violin Solos the (Whole) World Plays, or The 'Third' World Within Us" for Die Moltkerei catalogue, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - "Violin Solos the (Whole) World Plays, or The 'Third' World Within Us" Die MoltKerei, Koln [photographs by Ursula Frank], April, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 18, Box 51, Folder 4)
    - "Walking Song, Finding Voice" for Jeremias Schwarzer [score], 2005 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - "Wandering Still", 2017 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - "What can be said of our differences?" for Klang forum Wien [score], 2005 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - "Where are we going when we're standing still, looking backwards?" [score], 2002 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - "Why Bach? Pourquoi?", 2006; September 19, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Wind Chases the Sun" for Leonard Pettier [score], 2001 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - "From Wind/ing- Sheet Red Trees Reborn" dedicated to the memory of David Nathan Chain [score], 1999 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - "With Thoughts for Erik Satie...And Afterthoughts" [score], April, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Without Beginning or Ending" for L'Art pour L'Art [score], 2003 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - "Yosha's Morning Song" [score], 1972 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "Yosha's Morning Song Extended" [score], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "Z+X Tschaikowsky" an opera with Barbara Hammann [inkjet prints; photographs; documentation], March 12-14, 1996; June 28, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Art-Related Music Projects, 2009 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Original Scores and Part Pages, 2018-2019 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B: Other Musicians - Scores and Adaptations
    Subseries B: Other Musicians contains scores that are either made by other musicians specifically for Malcolm Goldstein to play or works of others that he created adaptations and critical editions of. Included in this series is material that was used for the critical edition of Charles Ives' work more of which can be found in Series II: Writing.
    Material is arranged by surname of the musician whose piece is reflected therein.
    - Byron, Michael - "Eighty Pieces for String Instruments", 1979; 1996 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Byron, Michael - "7' for Solo Violin", October 10, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Byron, Michael - "158 Pieces for String Instruments", 1979 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Cage, John - "Cheap Imitation" [annotated], 1977 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Cage, John - "Eight Whiskus", March, 1985; April 23, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Cage, John - "Four^6 (part 3)" Montreal [1 of 3], September 5, 2012; December 5, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Cage, John - "Four^6 (part 3)" Montreal [2 of 3], April 10, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Cage, John - "Four^6 (part 3)" HR recording [3 of 3], November 6, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Cage, John - "One^6" with "One^10", June, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Cage, John - "Ryoanji" [adaptation], [undated] (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Cage, John - "Score and Twenty Three Parts" "Anarchic Harmony" John Cage's 80th Birthday Festival, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Cage, John - "Theater Piece", February 26, 1995; November 17, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 20, Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Cage, John - "Variations II", June-October, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 21, Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Cage, John - "Variations II" Koln, June, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Corner, Philip - "Gamelon Corn", 1982 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Corner, Philip - "(gamelon) The Gold Stone", April, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Corner, Philip - "Violin Music for Malcolm Goldstein" with comments, [1995-2010] (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Epstein, Paul - "Changes 2" with correspondence, June 14, 1984; 1985 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Fang, Liv - Potluck Performances and Haskell Opera House Concert [photographs], July 8, 2005; August 18, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Garland, Peter - "Matachin Dances", October 1980- February 1981 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Garland, Peter - "Three Variations for Solo Violin", Winter, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Higgins, Dick - "Song for Malcolm", March 27, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Hellermann, William - "The Violin Between Us", 1980 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Ives, Charles - "In Re Con Moto Et Al" [Tone Roads], April, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Ives, Charles - "A Program of Music by Charles Ives" McMillan Theater, Columbia University [originally framed], [undated] (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Ives, Charles - "String Quartet No. 2" annotated for Tone Roads Concert (mid-1960's), [c. 1965] (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Ives, Charles - "Tone Roads No. 1" annotated by Malcom Goldstein and Jim Tenney for Tone Roads concert, New School, NYC, December, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Ives, Charles - "Trio" annotated by Malcolm Goldstein and John Kirkpatrick, February 19, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Johnson, Tom - "Imperfections" with correspondence, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Kasemets, Udo - "98 + memory echoes of John Cage", October 27, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Kasemets, Udo - "EGAD, a string theory for solo violin", 2004 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Kaul, Matthias - [photographs and inkjet prints], May, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Kaul, Matthias - "Last! Movement"; "Listen, this is for you", February, 1998; [undated] (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Mac Low, Jackson - "Vocabulary Gatha for Malcolm Goldstein", 1978 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Mott, David - "Meditation I" [with correspondence], 1981; November 13, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Oliveros, Pauline - "Malcolm's Birthday Piece"; "Thirteen Changes for MG", 1986 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Oliveros, Pauline - "Portrait of (Malcolm)", 1987 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Oliveros, Pauline - "The Witness", June 18, 1979; 1989 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Otte, Hans - "Alltagsmusik", 1989-1991 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Otte, Hans - "Alltagsmusik", 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Stravinsky, Igor - "Symphony of Psalms" [score], 1977 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Tenney, James - "Koan", August 16, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Transcriptions by Malcolm Goldstein, 1993, undated (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Webern, Anton - "Six Bagatelles" [score, notes] (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Wilson, Peter Niklaus - "Kraniche in Zweireiner", 1996 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Wolff, Christian - "Bread and Roses" [annotations by Malcolm Goldstein], [undated] (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Wolff, Christian -- "For 1, 2 or 3 People", 1999-2002 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Subseries C: Notebooks and Sketches
    Subseries C contains notebooks and loose sketches for projects. Notebooks contain drafts of scores and notes about music projects. Each notebook contains more than one music project within it.
    Each notebook has been given a number that was imposed by the archivist. This number is used to connect each notebook with the loose pages that were within it and falling out. These pages can be connected through this numbering system as well as through the photocopied pages of the notebook page that they were separated from.
    - Notebook 1: "Beethoven Piano Sonata"; "Lamentations of Jeremiah"; "Passacoglia", October 12, 1955; [undated] (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Notebook 1: [loose pages removed from last page of notebook], [undated] (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Notebook 2: Sketches for Improvisation including "Sirens for Edgard Varese"; "Plato Symposium"; complete program at Judson Church, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Notebook 2: [loose pages removed from first page of notebook], [undated] (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Notebook 2: "Plato Symposium" [discussion notes], [undated] (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Notebook 2: "John Cage Arts Award Materials for Student Performances", [1965-1970] (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Notebook 2: "Percussion Solo for Max", [undated] (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Notebook 2: "Sirens for Edgard Varese", [undated] (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Notebook 3: "Upon the Seashore of Endless Worlds", May 25, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Notebook 3: "From Center, Unfolding" Dance Positions, July, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Notebook 3: "Circular Breath-Space", February, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Notebook 3: "The Revival (Movement III from Charles Ives Sonata #2", [undated] (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Notebook 3: "Dance for Oracle" [dance instructions], [undated] (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Notebook 3: "For Violins and Violas", [undated] (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Notebook 3: "Sheet Metal and Worker", [undated] (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Notebook 3: "Cartridge Music" Tone Roads, [undated] (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Notebook 3: "Worded Music"; "Kaleidescope" [with various composition notes] [1 of 2], [undated] (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Notebook 3: "Thou Swell"; "Situations and Responses" for New School Composition Class [2 of 2], [undated] (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Notes: Various Unfinished Compositions - Includes "The Obscurity of Walls"; "Renga Interaction & Extended"; "Celestial Orchestra" [1 of 4], [undated] (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Notes: Various Unfinished Compositions - Includes "A Breaking of Vessels..."; "Trying to put it all together"; "On Hearing A Tractor At Midnight" [2 of 4], [undated] (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Notes: Various Unfinished Compositions - Includes "The Stars and Stripes Forever March", [undated] (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Notes: Various Unfinished Compositions - Includes "Baden Horspiel Soundscape"; "Marin's Song; Illuminated"; "Cantos III: Royalty House Blues"; "Between Hair and Wood/Changes" [4 of 4], [undated] (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Series II: Writing
  Series II comprises three subseries: Unpublished Drafts and Interviews, Published works, and Correspondence. Each subseries is described more fully below.
  - Subseries A: Unpublished Drafts and Interviews
    Subseries A contains unpublished draft versions of articles, lectures and interviews. This includes work on the critical edition of Ive's work that is in progress.
    Works are arranged alphabetically and reflect titles derived from Malcolm Goldstein. Interviews have been kept grouped together as they were upon arrival.
    - "An attempt to define what it is to be 'in the sound'", January 29, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - "Because a circle is not enough", June 15, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Brochures: "New Roots in Music and Dance" and "Soundings", [1970-1980] (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - "Charles Ives: Politics and Aesthetics" [Revised version of lecture with notes], 2004 (Box 12, Folder 25, Box 51, Folder 10)
    - From Wheelock Mountain: "Music: the process of living, sounding"; "Blueberry Picking", 1968 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - "The Gesture of Improvisation", 1982 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - "The Gesture of Improvisation" and "Reflections on the Politics of Improvisation" for Percusive Arts Society, October, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - "Improvisation as a process of discovery" for Aspekte de Freien Improvisation, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - "Improvisation" - Book Project, [undated] (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - "Improvisation: People Making Music" - New Music America Festival, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Improvisation Workshop and Notes [includes list of participants], [1997-1998] (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Improvisation Workshop and Notes [1 of 2], [1993] (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Improvisation Workshop and Notes [2 of 2], [1993] (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Improvisation Workshop and Notes - Opleidung Theater School, [1985-1993] (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Interview - American Music Series Oral History, Yale University [transcript], February 12, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Interview - conducted by Dough Kahn [transcript], May, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Interview - "The Improvisor" conducted by Thomas Gaudynski and Diana David, Summer, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Interview - Logos-blad Belgium [Dutch], September 9, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Interview - Mobius Newsletter vol.2 no.6 conducted by David Miller, April/May, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Interview - OP Magazine, Steve Peters at New Music America Festival- Walker Art Center, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Interview - conducted by Regina Beyer for Ear vol. 13 no.5, July/August, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Interview - Weiner Festwochen conducted by Grita Insam, 1982; 1983 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Ives Project - Preface and Sources, November 15, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Ives Project - Guidelines for Editors and Sources, [1976] (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Ives Project - Notes and Corrections, [undated] (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Ives Project - Correspondence, [1976-1979] (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Lecture Notes - "Politics of Improvisation"; "Koln Akademie Arts and Media Talk", [undated] (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Lecture Notes - "MaryAnn Baxter Memorial Lecture", April 10, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Lecture Notes - "Outline for a talk on Varese", [early 1970's] (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - "Marin's Song, Illuminated" some comments, 1979-1981 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - "Of Philip Corner" for Philip's CD program notes, May 12, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - (Opingalik Statement) - Untitled, September, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - "The Politics of Improvisation" - article form, 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "The Politics of Improvisation" original cards for Vienna presentation, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "The Politics of Improvisation" original cards, May 6, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "The Politics of Improvisation", 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - "The Politics of Improvisation" - German and English versions for performance in Europe, May 6, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - "The Practice of Music" proposal/syllabus, February 23, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - "Pro Musica Nova" Catalogue, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "Releasing Sounds/ Our Voice Through Objects" for EAR Magazine, May/June, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - "Scuttling a Space of Time, Slowly" - Basho poems, notes, 2014 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - "Searching the Sounding Line" - "Der Tanz der Dinge" [german], 1996 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "The Seasons: Vermont" for Soundings Magazine (never realized), 1983 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - "The Seasons: Vermont" Swedish Radio Company Music Department "Studio Onsdag" Program [swedish], October 3, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - "Soil" - with Masashi Harada [program notes], May 28, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - "Some Anecdotal Evidence" Journal of American Music, August/Winter, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 13)